this is our first road trip to
California we put out on our last
podcast and said who should we interview
when we come over here and about three
or four people I think three people
commented in the YouTube comments saying
Paul Vander clay you should check him
out and then a couple of people emailed
me separately to say go and check out
Paul so our audience has brought us
together and I'd love to know I mean
we're in your is this the Sunday School
Nursery yeah
hence the the giraffes behind you and
the camels behind me just getting that
out of the way now so Paul I'd love to
hear like where are we who are you and
why what's brought us together well my
name is Paul Vander clay and I'm the
pastor of Livingstone's Christian
Reformed Church here in Sacramento
California what's brought us together is
jordan peterson i about six seven months
ago
I've been following Jordan Peterson for
about a year and I'd been blogging about
him I've had a blog for years and at
some point I was reading Neil postman's
rereading the book I had read in the 80s
I'm using ourselves to death which talks
about media and the way it changes
messages and shapes message and empowers
message and I thought I should probably
do a video about Jordan Peterson and I
made a couple of them and I had had a
little I had 15 subscribers on my
youtube channel where I was doing a show
with Freddy Schuler who you probably met
this morning just something because he
wanted to do a TV show with me and
that's all I had done and then suddenly
there were more people watching my
channel and I began getting letters from
people talking about how helpful my
commentary had been for them to
understand Jordan Peterson and frame him
within a Christian context so I kept
doing it and I've continued to do it
since then and I've watched many of your
videos and very much appreciated them so
here we are it's quite a surprise to me
hmm
yeah cuz I guess my journey with Jordan
Peterson as well started probably about
a year ago my first
him wrote a blog about him and then
luckily got to interview him in Toronto
and since then like I I have a sense
like that there's Jordan Pederson
himself and then there's what he
represents and for me what I think he
represents is a kind of potential for
the reintegration of a Christian
tradition that I think the materialist
world has kind of lost and potentially a
kind of reintegration of the sacred
itself which is what I think I saw when
I first saw him I'm like wow this is
such a vital message for the times and
you you're coming from over I guess a
very different place in terms of you
live in that sacred world you live in
that Christian world so what what does
he represent to you the first thing I
saw was their Christians Christians read
this book that says we live under a dome
and God is up and the world is down and
there's people under the world they live
in that space during church and then
they go out into the world and we're on
a globe and we're flying through space
and when I listen to Jordan Peterson
church has always talked about God
coming from above and that right now is
getting nowhere with huge groups of
people and here I Jordan Peterson was
coming from below and he's trying to
connect heaven and earth again which is
where the why the conversation always
goes back to the physical nature of the
resurrection so I watched this and I
thought this is and then I listened to a
lot of people watching him saying I'm
interested in going to church and I'm
interested in exploring this and it was
very clear Jordan Peterson was rocketing
up the hierarchy and not everybody was
going to get a chance to sit down and
talk to him and I'm available and so
they find me and so then as a Christian
minister I'm a proxy that's right I'm
I'm down I'm way down at the low end of
the feeding chain which is okay by me
I like my pastor small Church I like
small things what's exciting about it is
we get to do what we're doing now
sitting talking face-to-face this is
what I enjoy yeah lots of things to pick
up on you remind me when you talk about
sort of Peterson talking about the
bottom-up nature of
I guess the bottom-up nature of religion
and religious revelation you might say
there's an echo of his conversation with
ben shapiro when ben shapiro was talking
about like he's obviously very into the
kind of jewish revelation and the
biblical stories being true and he was
Peterson was saying yes but you can also
get there another way there's there's
some sense in that the revelation from
below like evolved morality and the
psychological reality of the stories
like a very human level also matches
this sort of revelation from above of
this is somehow divinely like I guess in
in the history in history it would have
been this is these have come from God
it's sort of it's a sense of them both
coming together in some sense very much
so the john calvin so i'm a Calvinist
pastor calls the the census tamanna tata
switch says that god has built into us a
way to hear him I hadn't heard someone
making I hadn't heard someone making a
compelling case like this that was
actually getting traction with people
and was clear Peterson was getting
traction and so then I said I've got to
listen to this guy I've got to figure
out what he's saying and why it's
working and what how I should respond to
what's happening around him how is it
being as well because Peterson has
obviously began it been getting more and
more controversial and I've kind of felt
this as well sort of like you end up
getting in into conversations no he
didn't mean that it wasn't about that
how is how is that being like a people
started arguing with you or judging what
you're saying or how does that mean I
deeply suspect there are a number of
friends of mine that are deeply
concerned for me because of this jordan
peterson thing because they hear again
the sound bite world grabs a few things
jordan peterson is a bigot he's
transphobic he's homophobic he's you
know the godfather of the patriarchy
whatever he is and so paul but the thing
is they know me they know i'm not a
bigot they know they know where I was
raised they know who's in my church they
know they know me by my actions so what
to do with this
I've given Jordan Peterson in a sense a
year of my life what do you do with that
well they don't know what to do with
that so they're quiet and they watch and
they wait I I do think YouTube is a
place for people with little to lose and
I have a son who is you know might very
well have a career in politics he's
worked in politics and he just asked me
he says you know something you know I
see what you're doing and part of me
thinks I should get a youtube channel I
think no don't do that you're you're you
know you're 20-something years old
you're gonna get on there and you're
gonna start doing what I'm doing and who
knows what that's gonna mean twenty
years from now I'm in my 50s I can get
on there and I I've already got a pretty
good filter I know if I would say I'm
not gonna be a Christian anymore I'm
gonna be a Muslim I mean that would get
me into trouble so don't so I've already
got my internal filter so to a certain
degree in the little places that the
Christian Church is I've got my place on
the hierarchy I why don't I use the
status I have for what I think is right
if I don't do that what is that mean I
am you know then then suddenly I am all
of those things that on Sunday morning I
say I shouldn't be then I'm I'm
concerned about my status and I'm not
willing to do what I think Jesus did you
know why did Jesus do what he did it's a
crazy thing to imagine if you imagine
the story that he if he had this kind of
power of course skeptics up now I didn't
do miracles okay what he if he had this
kind of power he had this kind of
following well I throw it all away when
you could have talked your way out of
what was clearly you know ridiculous
charge that you would you would be
killed for well he he believed what he
said and he cared about people that this
world doesn't care anything about I want
to see people
people do that all the time I want to I
want to see that recognize I want to see
people do that because yes there are
these hierarchies and they are real but
what God says is I'm gonna go to the
absolute bottom and I'm gonna serve the
rest of you and if you think about a God
who won't even let himself be seen who
regularly gives us Sun and food and all
of these things God is the most humble
creature in the universe that's why it's
hard to see so I why not spend my life
doing that and people say well you're
gonna get rich and famous with this
Jordan Peterson thing I already made I'm
already able to feed my family and my
kids are you know they're into college
now so if I can if I can do well by them
what more do I have to ask for and just
to come back to your tell me a bit more
you're a pastor tell me about the
community and and kind of what's your
day-to-day life look like well the
community is an outrageously diverse
struggling community the this is this
would be a poor section of Sacramento
there are a lot of group homes where
there are people who are on permanent
disability for mental illness there's a
fair amount of drugs homelessness we
didn't have any homeless people or
untreated schizophrenic sin Church this
morning but that's fairly common for us
here how can we pray for each other this
morning day to day is dealing with that
community to a degree it's it's working
with my congregation talking to people
who come to me and so the Petersons
stuff kind of fit in except people are
coming to be now via YouTube and or via
emails or comments and I'm engaging with
in conversation with them it's a small
it's a small congregation which gives me
the opportunity to do what we're doing
today and you started putting out
commentaries on Peterson you've you
found like a lot of people following on
YouTube how's that being kind of going
from this
small community of what we had 20 or 30
people in church before to kind of
potentially a global audience at least
being contacted by people around the
world how's that being well it scared me
to death when it first started because
in two weeks I had you know a thousand
1,500 people listening to what I was
saying and I thought well this can't
keep at this pace because that would
destroy what I've been building here for
a long time eventually it tapered off
and I've learned that it's been at a
manageable pace and so I can both take
care of my congregation and interact
with people and that's and that's what I
like and has it been a learning
experience for you as it developed your
ideas or what's what's the process being
for you of kind of going from from here
a bit more out coming out into the world
and I've always been a lifelong learner
so I've always read philosophy read
history I've always done that but this
has probably been the most the most
highly charged fruitful learning
experience I've had in my life with a
possible exception of moving to the
Dominican Republic learning a new
language and having to live in another
culture because what happens is I have
very smart people from around the world
send me links and book ideas and
resources and push back on my videos and
it's it's been tremendously fun and an
incredible education and what do you
think you've learned the most from it
that the church the churches insularity
is both a natural byproduct of what she
has to do to create real community but
it's also its greatest hindrance to
actually speaking to people outside of
herself the church so many people
they've already toured impede erson put
them on the road to being interested in
church I've kind of given them another
nudge and then they start looking around
for church and it's just a disaster
and my heart my heart bleeds when I hear
that because what I would want as a
Christian pastor would be that they
would find a church
that could help them sort themselves out
where they could find community where
they could without fear explore whatever
crazy idea they have and talk about that
and and work that through and most
churches simply aren't interested in
that and it's it's a tragedy mmm they're
not interested I'm not capable or what
do you both how many pastors listen to
Jordan Peterson some more than will
admit to it but I have a small highly
permission giving Church and so I'll
have a meet up here in a few hours where
you know 15 to 20 people will come
together and we won't pray we won't do
communion I had one of my old-timers
stop in and listen once and I'm not sure
he knew what was going on but he trusts
me so if the pastor's doing this it must
be okay
and people are working on their stuff
will they become Christians certainly
not all of them but we opened the church
for a meetings all kinds of good things
for the community this is an important
thing for the community this is really
interesting to me it's like I guess
there's a there's a real tension in
Peterson's relationship with
Christianity and the Christian Church
because he doesn't describe himself as a
Christian and I'd love to get your kind
of thoughts on that because he's kind of
a like he's pulling people towards a
deeper appreciation of the Christian
story but it's in a slightly different
way to the church
can you pull that apart for me because I
can sort of sense there's a tension here
but I don't really understand it some
some of the tension some of the tension
is in Christianity itself what is a
Christian if you grew up in the Muslim
world and you came to North America you
would say almost everyone here is a
Christian and if you pull someone off
the street say are you a Christian
they might say yes they might say no so
there's a tremendous amount of ambiguity
in terms of the definition of a
Christian Peterson Jonathan pooja has
one of the better arguments I think he
says he's like Cyrus he's
who was this Persian Emperor who in the
Book of Isaiah Isaiah calls him the
servant of the Lord which is a
tremendously high saying in the Book of
Isaiah which then eventually gets
referred to Jesus but Cyrus is this
pagan Persian Emperor who has hundreds
of wives and you know destroys nations
and all of this but God used Cyrus to
send the Jews back to rebuild the temple
and Jonathan pojo and his Eastern
Orthodox frame I can see where that
really works for him I see a John the
Baptist vibe in Jordan Peterson John a
lot of people don't know John the
Baptist had a following that extended a
couple of centuries he was a huge deal
but then you know what did Jesus do and
what followed Jesus so Christians have
this huge debate people write me I'm
praying for Jordan Peterson it becomes a
Christian other people write me know
he'd better not become a Christian now
because none of the atheists will listen
to him well I'm content to let Jordan
Peterson B Jordan Peterson and let God
do with Jordan Peterson whatever God's
going to do I I'm one of the things you
learn in ministry is not to to quickly
define people because people are people
their enormous ly complicated and people
you might put them in a category they're
in the Christian Reformed Church if you
know enough Christian inform doctrine
and you you quiz them enough oh there
there are a hodgepodge of all kinds of
beliefs why isn't Jordan Peterson so I
I'm comfortable not answering the
question I guess I got a sense that like
for me certainly like I always had a
sort of spiritual leanings I studied
Buddhism and Hinduism study philosophy
at university and I've always had a kind
of spiritual side to to my interests and
it wasn't really until listening to
Peterson that I kind of was really able
to frame the Christian story in a new
way and really understand the
sophistication of the Christian kind of
metaphors and the idea of dying to your
cert like that kind of the idea of the
Cross of like one dies to oneself every
moment to be reborn and has to allow the
dead wood to die off all these kind of
great very very meaningful a very
profound ideas
but there's a sense that he's almost
pointing away to an integration of the
Christian story that points beyond it in
some ways that that I wonder if that's
kind of threatening to the idea of like
the Christian Church based around a set
of I'd an ideology as much as a sort of
fixed idea or a dogma
he's almost pointing beyond that in some
ways that is that part of the tension
maybe I when I listen to him I think
he's actually only going halfway for
example if you listen closely to his
Easter videos the gospel for him is pick
up your very heavy cross and drag it
uphill and if you do so you will
experience meaning and you'll sort out
your life and you'll make the world
better there's a there's a stoicism to
Peterson and as I then one of the person
one of the people who watches me a lot
of people who watch me then they go to
his things and they ask him questions
they ask him questions that I'm playing
with and they write me back and so one
person at one of his at one of his book
tours got the question through that said
okay what's at the top of the hill
you're pulling the cross up and I'm too
tired I would need too much time to
unpack that I don't think that's a Dodge
I think Peterson is working as hard as
he can to figure out what's at the top
of the hill in Christianity none of us
know that you know Paul says well I've
been to the third heaven and we have
these images of the the kingdom of God
and they're all built into this rich
this rich symbolic system but none of us
can describe it so I I think actually
he's he's where he's really out right
now is a certain stoicism that is that
people are finding tremendously helpful
I think at some point they're going to
say what's at the top of the hill it
can't be too utopian because he's made
it clear that we're not going to arrive
at that in this frame so is there there
there and
I was reminded in the in the church
service today about Young's because I
get young as his his metaframe that he's
using to appreciate all of this and
Young had an interesting relationship
with God where he was asked do you
believe in God and he said I don't
believe I know which there's a kind of
interesting connection with Christianity
there because fundamental as far as I
understand it Christianity is the idea
that we need faith because we don't know
there must be doubt and doubt must
coexist with faith so yeah I'm
interested what you make of that well
Young was the son of a Swiss Reformed
pastor a very depressed man apparently
his father was and a rather unhappy man
my definition of a Christian and that I
tell my congregation is do you trust
Jesus more than you trust yourself well
what does that mean we have to unpack
that and that scales in every moment you
know I'm doing an interview with you I
don't know you
unfortunately I'm not high enough up the
hierarchy that you know rebel wisdom
destroys paul van der clay so we extend
trust and obviously this is a very small
stakes thing but life is full of huge
stakes things and who how where can I
place my trust how do I know that Jordan
Peterson I don't think he's a flim-flam
artist I've watched people on my whole
life I don't think he's disingenuous at
all I think he's enormous ly open and
making himself vulnerable I have a sense
of knowing that could I be wrong you
know I could be wrong but you live with
what you know you don't have any other
choice so I was raised by great parents
and I was I learned to love Jesus as a
child and I've seen no reason to give it
up now now if you ask me if I trust
Jesus more than I trust myself no way
I'm a you know part of what's nice about
being a Calvinist as I can say I'm a
wretched sinner and I'm a really lousy
Christian and you can still be a pastor
and be that in the Calvinist Church
yeah cuz after the service today I was
talking to some of the people who came
and one guy I was talking to for a
little while and then he said I you a
believer and I couldn't answer I didn't
know what he meant I was like I I just
and he obviously wanted me to say yes or
no and I didn't know like what that
question means and I guess I came to
what did I say I think I said something
like I've got a deeper appreciation of
the Christian stories I've got a deeper
appreciation of the essential
metaphorical rightness of a lot of it
and it became quite a long answer how
should I answer that question this is
part of the insularity
of the Christian bubble because people
say Peterson is copping out by saying
you know do you believe in God what do
you mean by belief what do you mean by
God when Peterson says that I think
Peterson's a hundred percent correct
when this guy asked you are you believer
he's out he's doing code talk within a
little bubble you could have said yes
and a whole bunch of things he would
have imagined that I don't know you very
well but probably aren't true for your
life you don't go to church every week
you don't tithe you there's not all
these practices built into you but to
say no well believer in what so as a
Christian pastor often when people
engage in code talk I pause them and I
can do this because I'm a pastor and say
what do you mean by saved well then you
find out what they mean and then you can
say okay and move it around a little bit
see what you can do with the
conversation so I think you answered
very well actually he's probably
confused and went on with his life
because he was he was looking for the
secret handshake and this is what
happens in Christian churches and so
people listening to Jordan Peterson come
into a Christian Church they get asked a
question like that well right away now I
know I don't belong I don't know the
handshake so that's a hard thing there's
a really interesting topic because I
guess how does the Christian Church
absorb deal with and they capitalized
but at least kind of Italy find a way
of making use of the kind of what seems
to be a bit of an awakening going on of
people who are watching these biblical
stories and getting an awful lot from it
because at the moment isn't they're not
really receptive or able to receive how
do they do it I don't know that they
will which is sad so well I started a
meet-up and in some ways that meetup for
me is is it a church plant no cuz it's
not a church we don't have sacraments we
don't have all those things of Church is
a a church that's a really complicated
question because look at what a look at
how a a started look at what people have
to do to get into it I've had people
join this church because they're in naa
25 years and they said I need something
my higher power needs a better
definition okay well let's keep let's
keep talking so I it may be and this it
may be that there is a revival of sorts
that happens in Jordan Peterson's wake
but this is the history of the church if
you look at the church and see all these
tiny little sub movements or they all
started because something happened that
put a twist on everything and a whole
community came in look at Methodism this
has happened again and again and again
in history will there be another little
group of churches that's get started
because Jordan Peterson brought a whole
new thing to people and it didn't fit
into the regular Church and so here it
begins I don't know could happen
Peterson ISM Peterson I am gonna get in
trouble for that for saying what I just
said I know but I'm old enough to not
care too much I was actually raised a
Methodist
my parents were Methodists which
probably only up until I was sort of 10
years old 11 years old something like
that but so I don't know what it means
so much except except that it was more
about trying to understand how Jesus
would have lived but it's more that's
what I understood of Methodism it was
more about looking looking
him him as a as a guide mm-hmm was that
that be right yeah almost every new
church movement and heresy starts
because a group of people say I want to
know the real Jesus and and you guys
have lost your way right yeah and so
then they start their own little thing
and then that goes for religions are
very long things goes for a few hundred
years and then I regularly have
Jehovah's Witness come to my door and if
I have enough time I'll sit them down
and I'll start asking them questions
about what they really believe and yeah
they're heretics for the jobs witnesses
because other stuff is coming into them
and that process is always happening so
well I'm not God and I'm happy to not be
him at the moment Jordan Peterson's
going into some debates for Sam Harris
if you listen to the Vancouver ones I
have yeah what was your impression of
the Vancouver debates I thought they
were helpful in terms of I think the
optics of those debates are as important
as the as the content of them I didn't
hear anything out of Peter almost his
axioms were new and I wish he'd put them
on his website but most of what I heard
out of Sam Harris you could hear on many
many of his podcasts but the fact that
these two individuals are sitting down
talking engaging in a productive way
that's to me that's a win and I that's
what happens at our meetups this is what
I'd love to see more as a Christian
minister I long for the opportunity to
sit down with people and just hear what
they think and talk about it and there's
not nearly enough of that happening in
churches or outside of churches and so
to watch that happen and that people pay
to hear it that's I think it's just
terrific and do you think that there's
any flexibility on either side o do you
think sam Harris might kind of turn
around and just and say actually you're
right there are
truth has to be embedded in stories I've
realized that this whole atheism
rationality thing is is actually only a
partial truth and you're right there are
too far up the hierarchy to let that
happen but what are we doing
why so some people come to my meetup and
they say I used to be right there with
Sam Harris now I'm not so sure why
because our mental minions are in there
listening and our conscious self is only
this little part of it and they're all
used Jonathan heights the elephant is
making decisions the rider is just
giving rationale so Harris's way up the
hierarchy some high profile people have
flipped both ways so is it possible he
could in the future yeah is it likely no
but that's not what the point is about
the point is let's hear your argument
let's hear your argument what do I think
of it so I started making videos because
I'm watching these conversations and I'm
I want to butt in I want to have a part
I want to be a part of it and YouTube
kind of let me be a part of it and
that's what's that's what's happened
since now I'm having these conversations
with dozens of people and it's wonderful
well what's happened is Peterson is
getting incorporated I mean it's one
brain here why do I start studying
people like Peterson it's to incorporate
him and when he says things in a certain
way I think play it's a lot better way
to say it so what am I gonna do I'm
gonna use it pastors are thieves we're
not just Liars we're thieves and when we
hear something that works well I'm gonna
grab that I'm gonna work that forever
Peterson's whole says it all the time
finally gets into my thick skull
you know our values stack up in
hierarchies well in my Sunday School
class I said right now in our culture we
have a confusion between love and
kindness love is higher in the hierarchy
than kindness as well it should be when
kindness is at the top of the hierarchy
that's the permissive parent who gives
their kid whatever he wants the loving
parent sometimes will say no to their
child
so kindness is lower on the hierarchy
the whole story of Jesus a number of
years ago when I was studying the book
first
Peter I realized the New Testament is
all about status and hierarchies and
it's got this crazy story where Jesus on
one hand says you're all equal and it's
like oh that's radically egalitarian and
then he says but I'm at the top of the
hierarchy and Jesus is about to serve
Jesus gathers his disciples together and
everybody in their mind has this
hierarchy and Jesus at the top and
they're about to celebrate the the the
Exodus dinner and Jesus stands up he
takes off his clothes I told my Sunday
School class said imagine if I step up
and take off my clothes here we'd call
nine-one-one stood up take off his you
know stripped down his underwear I
wrapped a towel around him and starts
washing his disciples feet and his
disciples they're all work in the house
no no no Jesus says if you don't let me
wash your feet you can have no part of
me Peter says well wash my whole body
just like the feet are enough and he
washes their feet
what what's jesus doing with the
hierarchy it's just he's becoming a
servant and almost every text has this
dynamic so the top becomes the bottom
and because the top becomes the bottom
he's really at the top we have this in
our national conversation who is the
president's supposed to be the servant
of all and the president so you know the
captain of the Titanic go down with the
ship why make sure everyone else is off
and then you and we all know this this
is deep within us now you might ask well
this is this only Christianity or listen
to Peterson
well maybe it's even deeper still so
what does that mean the Christianity is
actually an outgrowth of of the deeper
principles that's right which is exactly
what CS Lewis says in the line in which
in the wardrobe when Aslan allows
himself to be killed on the stone table
and then the stone table breaks and CS
Lewis says well there's a deeper magic
because he gave up his life for Edmund
the rebel and now Aslan is arisen and
the new reign of Aslan begins in winter
istic is gone
so this is the Christian story and it's
all over the place in our culture but
people don't recognize it this is the
most infuriating argument that you could
ever use as an atheist which is you're a
Christian pretending not to be which is
kind of it's yeah it you could imagine
how how that would feel to someone like
Sam Harris if Peterson said to him well
look at your actions look at the way
that you behave you cannot help but be a
Christian because this morality is
deeply embedded in everything that
you've it's in every fiber of your being
yeah yeah you you're not gonna get away
from it and I think Sam era should turn
around and say yeah you're more of a
materialist than you want to admit and I
think that's true - because we're it's
it's all mixed within us and I think
this huge culture war we see happening
in the West is a Christendom civil war
because I can establish you know
same-sex marriage I can establish a
person perfectly reasonable
understanding why you know gay people's
relationship should be sanctified by the
church
I can also argue the other way around
and so in an ancient in the ancient
world ancient Egypt or ancient Rome
would be like you know marry your gay
lover well what would you do that for I
mean that makes no sense to them but wow
there's this long line of things that
have happened to marriage through
Christianity and all of this we're just
so deeply embedded in the whole thing
that we're just having Christian
arguments back and forth and you might
even argue that as Western Western
culture or as Scott Alexander he's a
blogger argues universal culture
continues to dominate around the world
well in a funny way evangelization is
happening by secularists who claim there
is no God because these ideas that if
Christianity deeply embedded in them are
just being picked up by people of all
over the world and there's a lot of
people now calling themselves who used
to call themselves atheists now call
themselves Christian atheist yeah yeah
isn't that crazy
yeah not I think it's tremendously fun
because well what's more fun
talking about what's closest to our
hearts and gives us meaning and that's
you can't have no more fun than sitting
in a room and doing that for a few hours
I just appreciate the chance to do this
and it's it's an amazing thing that I
sit there and talk to the camera and
people watch it I remember after I did
one in my family's like what are they
watching I said here I'll play it for
you and you know it's horrible watching
yourself on there and I think why does
anybody watch this you know who in their
right mind would be spending two hours
listening to this but they do and so as
long as I keep getting emails from
people which I do every day you know oh
wow I'm so glad you're doing this this
is really helping me I don't know that
they could tell me how it's helping them
which is kind of a crazy thing but they
feel a sense of these are our mental
minions doing their work back there and
they're saying this is this is helping
me enough that I'm motivated to get to a
computer and dig up your email and write
you this message and I say if that's
happening I'll keep doing it as long as
it's helpful so so I do it cool thank
you very much thank you my pleasure